A Guide to the Dr. Edward Riley papers, Undated
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Dr. Edward Riley Papers n.d.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS2007.8
.25 linear feet.
Riley, Dr. Edward
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer, 2007
Biographical Information
Dr. Edward Riley was Director of Research at Colonial Williamsburg. He was appointed in 1954 and retired in 1976.
Scope and Content
A series within the 20th Century Collections, the Dr. Edward Riley Papers have been divided into two subseries: Assorted and Gooch Notes. The Assorted subseries contains documents donated by Riley's widow, Annette, to Riley's successor, Cary Carson. Several boxes were given to Carson, and the Historical Research Department sorted through before transfering the papers to Special Collections. Riley's research on William Gooch comprises the other subseries. Per CW Historian Linda Rowe, Riley intended to publish Gooch's letters.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in series.
Index Terms
Persons:
Gooch, William, Sir, 1681-1751
Family Names:
Baylor family
Corporate Names:
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation; Tennessee Emigration Society
Subjects:
Governors - Virginia
Geographical Names:
Louisiana - Ordinance
Genre and Form Terms:
Notes
Contents List
- Papers
  - Assorted (Box 1)
    - Baylor Family papers, 1858-1887
    - Contents, Robert R. Thurston Papers, Filson Club, Louisville, KY
    - Letters
      - Lockwood, D. to Gov. Peter Causey, November 28, 1857
      - Reese, George to Dr. Riley, May 10, 1974
    - Manuscripts, assorted (photocopies)
    - Memo, N.M. Mertz to Dr. Riley, September 11, 1974
    - Music manuscripts, undated (3 pieces)
    - Notice, Tennessee Emigration Society (manuscript plat on verso), Ca. 1869
    - Ordinance (printed), Dissolving union between Louisiana and other states, Ca. 1811
    - Speech, Helen Bullock, CWF Archivist, September 8, 1938
    - Transcript, Earl of Dunmore to Earl of Dartmouth (Extract), March18, 1774
  - Gooch Notes (n.d.)
    - Afterpieces
    - Assorted topics
    - Books
    - Comedies
    - Entertainments
    - Miscellaneous
    - Non-transcribed material. 1727-1735
    - Old houses
    - Tragedies
    - Transcribed material
      - Prior to 17271727-1728
      - 1729-1731
      - 1732-1734
      - 1735-1736
      - 1737-1738 June
      - 1739
      - 1740-1747
    - Williamsburg, mentions in Pennsylvania Gazette